Justin Kyle Torres

Pasadena, California | Cell: 818-403-5405 Personal Website | Github | LinkedIn | justintorres56@gmail.com | Itch.io

SUMMARY

An impact-driven and highly-organized software engineer with **6 years of professional software development experience** contributing **full-stack code** with **a specialization in front-end** for building user-centric web apps. Multi-disciplinary creator in video games, music, and other media in free time.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Proficient: Git, React, JavaScript, TypeScript, Next.js, Node.js, HTML, CSS/SASS, C#/.dotnet Experienced: Redux, Unity, Godot, Python, Flask, Java, Google Cloud Platform, SQL, GraphQL

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Experienced as a communicative technical lead in launching multiple products and websites
- Reduced content production time by around 33% for creating immersive learning content (Strivr)
- Refactored and optimized an initial page load to reduce its initial fetchsize by ~200% (Ironman)

WORK EXPERIENCE

IRONMAN Group (August 2024 - Present)

Senior Next.js Developer

- Build highly-user focused features to drive user engagement for a modern web portal powering a delightful experience for thousands of athletes to manage and view info for results and registrations
- Coordinate the launch for multiple brand websites under different global and regional specifications
- **Utilize Azure's cloud platform and CRM** to power highly-scalable infrastructure
- **Improve developer pain points** by writing clear and concise documentation for new and existing features and building out new CI/CD workflows

STRIVR (May 2019 - January 2024)

Senior Software Engineer (Promotion)

April 2022 - January 2024

Software Engineer II (Promotion)

September 2020 - April 2022

STRIVR, Software Engineer Intern (May 2018 - August 2018)

- Led and collaborated in design reviews cross-functionally with peers, Product, and Design to provide feedback, make data-driven decisions, and choose the right technologies to deliver project milestones
- Actively triaged, debugged, and resolved high urgency issues and bugs at a short notice
- **Provide impactful and supportive mentorship to junior-level teammates and peers** through in-depth code feedback, regular check-ins, peer coding sessions, and constant support
- Shipped features end-to-end with contributions across the tech-stack both front-end and back-end
- Reduced software crashes by over 50% through rigorous code-testing and process improvements

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science Loyola Marymount University | Los Angeles, CA | May 2019